nikonusa.com 2019-05-20

# Nikon Privacy Policy

_Updated May 12, 2017  
_

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING A NIKON OWNED WEBSITE, AS DEFINED BELOW IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  WHEN YOU USE A NIKON OWNED WEBSITE YOU ARE SUBJECT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. DO NOT USE ANY NIKON OWNED WEBSITE OR ANY OTHER COMMUNICATION POINT AS DESCRIBED BELOW IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, IF YOU DO NOT WANT TO BE SUBJECT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

This Privacy Policy applies to all information received by Nikon Inc. (“Nikon,” “we,” “our” or “us”) through various on-line and/or off-line points of communication (collectively, the “Communication Points”), including but not limited to the following:

(a) this Nikon website and any other Nikon websites including any of its microsites or subsites (collectively, “Nikon Owned Websites”).  Nikon Owned Websites are the property of Nikon or its licensors;

(b) Nikon’s social media pages on Non-Nikon Owned Websites, as defined in Section 6  below (e.g., Nikon’s official/verified pages on Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Instagram, Google+, Flickr and/or Vimeo), which post a link to a Nikon Owned Website containing this Privacy Policy; and

(c) Other electronic, in-person, hard copy written or other means by which you may provide us with information, such as by purchasing products from Nikon’s on-line store, by participating in Nikon-related contests, sweepstakes and/or other promotions, by redeeming a Nikon-related offer, by communicating with Nikon at trade shows or events, by registering and/or attending Nikon School sessions and events, by presenting products for service, and/or by registering your product.

    1. Our Commitment to Privacy
    2. Notice to California Residents
    3. The Information We Collect
    4. How We Use Collected Information
    5. Who We Share Information With
    6. Links to Non-Nikon Owned Sites
    7. Online Behavioral Advertising
    8. Do Not Track Signals
    9. Our Commitment to Information Security
    10. Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy
    11. How To Access or Update Your Information
    12. Your Privacy Preferences Regarding Personally Identifiable Information – Opting In/Out
    13. Changes To Privacy Policy
    14. How To Contact Us

**1\. Our Commitment to Privacy**  
Nikon recognizes that the protection of information that it receives from you is very important. Collecting information allows Nikon to better understand and to be more responsive to you, as well as to develop and maintain websites relevant to your needs, and assists us in managing our business better. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. 

**2\. NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**  
If you are a California resident, you may, one time per calendar year, request a notice regarding the categories of personally identifiable information disclosed by Nikon (if any) during the immediately preceding 12-month period to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes, and the name and address of any such third parties.  To obtain such a notice, please send a written request by postal mail to Nikon Inc., 1300 Walt Whitman Road, Melville, New York 11747, Attention: Legal Department.

**3\. The Information We Collect  
** We collect both Non-Personally Identifiable Information and Personally Identifiable Information, each defined below, that you provide to us through the Communication Points.   

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information** is information that cannot be used to identify you or to contact you and is information not associated with a specific personal identity. It includes information that we (or our third party service provider) collect automatically from you by tracking your use of the Nikon Owned Websites, using technology and methodology that enables tracking, such as cookies, pixels, web beacons, log files and other tracking technologies (collectively, “Cookies”).  A Cookie is a small file of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it can later be read back from that browser.  Information that a Cookie collects may include but is not limited to information such as domain type, browser version, service provider, internet protocol address, time spent and web pages visited, as well as information searched for on our Nikon Owned Websites. Cookies help a website recognize a returning visitor for purposes of saving certain preferences that the visitor set while previously browsing the website. This tracking through the use of cookies will not by itself reveal anything to us about you personally or provide us with any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, e-mail address or other personally identifiable information. Non-Personally Identifiable Information may also include information that you, at your option, voluntarily provide us through any of the other Communication Points and includes but is not limited to information such as your hobbies and interests, gender, age, level of education, photographic skill level as well as your purchases of and your experience with our products. 

**Personally Identifiable Information** is information collected from the Communication Points that is associated with a person’s name or personal identity and can be used to identify or contact you. It includes but is not limited to such information as your name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number (mobile and/or landline), fax number, and credit/debit card information. We do not knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from children under the age of thirteen. 

**4.  How We Use Collected Information  
**Nikon uses collected information (both Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information) to provide you with the goods, services or information that you request, and also to help us better understand the needs and interests of consumers so that we may more closely meet your needs.  For example, we may use Personally Identifiable Information to help you complete a transaction or order with us, to respond to your inquiries and requests, to provide and update you on our customer services and support, to notify you of promotional or special offers, to communicate with you about our products and services, to allow you to participate in an interactive feature, to invite you to participate in surveys about our products and/or services, to send you information about Nikon products, services, promotions, events, firmware or software updates, and service advisories, to suggest how to get more enjoyment from your Nikon products and photography, to post reviews or comments that you have submitted to Nikon, and/or to help us determine other Nikon products, services or information that may be of interest to you (see Section 12 below, “Your Privacy Preferences Regarding Personally Identifiable Information-Opting In/Out” regarding communications to you). Personally Identifiable Information in the form of credit/debit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention.

We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to increase the functionality and user friendliness of our Nikon Owned Websites, to improve the design, content and visitor experience of all of our Communication Points, and/or to deliver interest-based advertising as described in this Privacy Policy (see Section 7 below, “Online Behavioral Advertising” regarding interest-based advertising). We may also use Personally Identifiable Information and/or Non-Personally Identifiable Information for research purposes such as analyzing how visitors use and navigate our Nikon Owned Websites. In addition, we may take your Personally Identifiable Information and make it Non-Personally Identifiable Information, either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics, such as your name, that make the information personally identifiable to you, i.e., de-personalizing your information. Given the nature of this information, there are no restrictions under this Privacy Policy on Nikon’s right to aggregate or de-personalize your Personally Identifiable Information, and use and/or share with third parties the resulting Non-Personally Identifiable Information in any way.   

**5\. Who We Share Information With**  
Nikon may disclose Personally Identifiable Information to companies affiliated with Nikon, such as our parent company and/or unaffiliated third parties working on our behalf or for us or with us, such as agents, service providers, consultants, shippers, processors, vendors and suppliers, for the purposes of enabling them to respond to your requests to us or your purchase of products, services or information, for fulfilling Nikon-related contests, sweepstakes, promotions and/or Nikon-related offers, assisting us in understanding your needs and interests so that we can better provide you with products, services or information, or for the other purposes discussed above in Section 4 of this Privacy Policy. All such affiliated and unaffiliated parties who have access to Personally Identifiable Information are required by Nikon to keep confidential such information and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Nikon and as otherwise required by law. Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, Nikon will not share Personally Identifiable Information with third parties without your permission, unless to (a) comply with any law, subpoena, regulation or court order; (b) respond to requests from governmental authorities; and/or (c) help prevent fraud or to protect the safety, rights, property or security of Nikon as well as that of third parties. 

**6\. Links to Non-Nikon Owned Sites** **  
** The Communication Points may include links to and/or from other websites and/or social media platforms which are not owned by Nikon and are owned by companies or parties which are either affiliated or unaffiliated with Nikon (collectively, “Non-Nikon Owned Websites”). These links are provided to you as a matter of convenience and for informational purposes only.  When you access links to or from a Non-Nikon Owned Website, you are not on a Nikon Owned Website. We do not endorse or make any representations about Non-Nikon Owned Websites, and we are not responsible for and we disclaim all warranties, express or implied, as to the practices, privacy, content or security of such Non-Nikon Owned Websites.  You are responsible for reviewing, and we encourage you to review the terms of use, privacy and any other policies of such Non-Nikon Owned Websites. 

**7\. Online Behavioral Advertising**  
Nikon may participate in targeted advertising, whereby you may receive advertisements that may be of interest to you on Nikon Owned Websites and/or Non-Nikon Owned Websites from Nikon, third party advertisers or advertising networks. These advertisements are selected based on an assessment of your on-line browsing behavior, search activities and/or demographic information.  We do not share Personally Identifiable Information for this purpose.  
If you receive a behaviorally targeted advertisement as stated above, you may click on the icon displayed on the advertisement to receive more information, including instructions for opting out from receiving further advertisements from that particular advertising network.  Your opt-out choices may depend on your specific device or browser settings and some websites or browsers may have different features regarding your ability to choose which ads to display or opt out from receiving.  Please refer to the applicable website that you are visiting for additional information.    
For ad networks or other third parties who follow the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising, or who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”), you can opt-out of receiving targeted ads from such parties by visiting the opt-out pages on the DAA website at [www.aboutads.info/choices/](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and/or the NAI website at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

**8.   Do Not Track Signals**  
Some web browsers may have a “do not track” option that allows you to opt out of having your on-line activities tracked.  As a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed regarding this technology, the Nikon Owned Websites are not currently set up to respond to this feature, and we do not take action to respond to such “do not track” signals.

**9\. Our Commitment To Information Security**   
Information security is important at Nikon, and while no security measure is perfect or impenetrable and we cannot guarantee the security of the information that you provide to us, you can be assured that we maintain physical, electronic and administrative measures and safeguards and periodically review these security measures and safeguards to protect your Personally Identifiable Information from unauthorized or inappropriate access and use.  

**10\. Our Commitment To Children's Privacy**   
Our Communication Points are not directed at minors, and we do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from or about children under the age of thirteen. Should any parent or guardian discover that his/her child has provided personal information to Nikon, please contact Nikon at <https://support.nikonusa.com/app/contact> to have such information deleted from our records.  

**11\. How To Access or Update Your Information** **  
** You can access, edit, delete and update any Personally Identifiable Information that you provided to us by visiting your profile page on [www.nikonusa.com](https://www.nikonusa.com/) (if you are a registered user) or by contacting us at <https://support.nikonusa.com/app/contact>.  We use this procedure to better safeguard your Personally Identifiable Information.  To protect your privacy and security, we will also take steps to verify your identity before granting you access to edit or update your Personally Identifiable Information.  

**12\. Your Privacy Preferences Regarding Personally Identifiable Information-Opting In/Out** **  
** You can opt out of receiving promotional communications from Nikon by notifying us that you do not wish to receive such information by contacting us at [Nikon Email Preferences](https://support.nikonusa.com/ci/documents/detail/2/eof) (if you are a registered user), by contacting us at <https://support.nikonusa.com/app/contact>, or by contacting us in writing at Nikon Inc., 1300 Walt Whitman Road, Melville, New York 11747, Attention: Senior Manager, Customer Relations.  Please note that if you have opted out of receiving promotional communications from us, Nikon may still send you non-promotional communications (such as, for example, information about your accounts or purchases).  In addition, in the event you have opted out but in the future desire to receive promotional information from Nikon, you may opt in by contacting us at [Nikon Email Preferences](https://support.nikonusa.com/ci/documents/detail/2/eof). 

**13\. Changes To Privacy Policy**  
By visiting any of the Communication Points, or otherwise providing Nikon with your information, you are subject to this Privacy Policy and thus consent to our collection and use of your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Nikon reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy, including our collection and use and related business practices, at any time by posting updated text on our Nikon Owned Websites, however we will not materially reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy with respect to previously provided information, without your consent.  Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective at the time they are posted to our Nikon Owned Websites.  For this reason, it is your responsibility and Nikon encourages you to review this Privacy Policy each time you visit any of our Nikon Owned Websites.  

**14\. How To Contact Us**   
If you have any questions, comments or concerns with respect to our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy statement, please feel free to contact us at Nikon Inc., 1300 Walt Whitman Road, Melville, New York 11747, Attention:  Legal Department.

Back to Top
